hey everybody welcome to this a2
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram you ready
so today i'm gonna talk about manners
what are manners the word manners
refers to the way people behave
in social situations so
i'm going to talk about good manners and
bad manners in the us
and compare it to other countries
specifically we're gonna focus on
dining etiquette the word etiquette
is another word for manners
dining etiquette is fun to talk about
because there are many differences
throughout the world
when it comes to this topic in the u.s
for example it's not polite to make
a lot of noise while you're eating it's
not polite
to chew your food loudly or with your
mouth open
and it's not polite to sip your drink
or soup loudly the word sip
refers to the act of drinking or
consuming something like this
and if you sip something loudly
we say that you're slurping to be honest
this is pretty hard for me to avoid
when i eat soup i always slurp it
my wife always lectures me about this
and tells me not to do it especially
when we're in public
however in places like japan
sipping or even slurping your food
loudly is not considered rude
in fact it's considered rude if you
don't slurp your soup if you eat ramen
in japan
you're supposed to eat it like this
so my bad habit wouldn't be a problem
in japan interesting huh here's another
similar example in the u.s it's
considered
very rude to burp in public
burping is the sound you make with your
throat
after you eat or drink something
like soda so in america
you definitely won't hear people burping
in restaurants
however in many places in china
burping after you eat your meal isn't
rude
it can actually be a compliment to the
chef
it tells the chef that you liked the
food
i think this is a pretty interesting
difference
between manners in the us and china
something else that's considered good
etiquette
in the u.s is to politely refuse
when someone offers you food if someone
offers you
food in a situation where you didn't
plan to eat together
it's polite to refuse at least the first
offer for example let's say
you're at someone's house and you're not
good friends with them and they offer to
make you
some food you can say something like
oh that's okay you don't have to do that
then the person often offers again
and then maybe you accept the second
offer
or maybe you don't it's not rude to
refuse
offers for food i do this a lot
even if i do want the food this
is seen as polite in the u.s because you
don't
want to inconvenience other people
however in mexico and in many latin
american countries
you're supposed to eat the food that
you're offered
it can be considered rude if you don't
eat
what's offered to you this is definitely
a cultural difference
another interesting thing about mexican
dining etiquette is the way that people
sometimes say no thank you for example
if you're at the dinner table and
someone offers to give you more bread or
something
it's common to do this people might
do this while saying no thank you
or if their mouth is full of food they
might just
put their hand up like this without
saying anything
however in the us and in many
other countries it would be rude to do
this
to someone that's another big difference
okay one last example of good
dining etiquette in america is
keeping your elbows off the table
when you're eating you're not supposed
to put your elbows on the table
like this that being said i think that
putting your elbows on the table has
become more
acceptable in recent years nowadays
many parents don't lecture their
children
for putting their elbows on the table
it's seen as
normal now alright now i'm going to ask
you some questions
about today's video to see how well you
understood
number one what's another word for
manners number two in which country
is slurping your soup acceptable
and number three in which country or
region is it considered rude to refuse
food okay remember to subscribe to the
channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
for more english tips and lessons i'll
see you next time
you